marketplace-live.com 2018-08-19

# Privacy Policy | Marketplace Business Simulations

This Privacy Policy applies to the following domain names and all web sites (each a "Site" and, collectively, the “Sites”) maintained by Innovative Learning Solutions, Inc. DBA Marketplace Simulations (“Marketplace Simulations,” “we” or “us”) under the following domain names: 

  * marketplace-simulation.com
  * marketplacesimulation.com
  * business-simulation.com
  * marketplace-game.com
  * onlinegbg.com
  * marketplace-live.com
  * retail-game.com
  * roman-era.com
  * ilsworld.com
  * ilshome.com
  * map-mind.com
  * marketplacebike.com
  * marketplacesim(s).com

and all of their subdomains and web sites associated with them respectively. Marketplace Simulations offers several learning applications (the “Learning Tools” or the “Games”) on the Sites. These Learning Tools include Marketplace® business simulation, Marketplace Live® business simulation, Global Business Game, Retail Management Game, Roman History Game, and Marketplace Microsimulations® that are hosted on the Sites.

### 1\. Collection of personally-identifiable information

Marketplace Simulations collects personally-identifiable information (such as your last name, first name, postal address, telephone number, billing information, email address, birthday, gender, language, country, time zone, and links to social media profiles) that you submit through the Site, and email, telephone, fax or mail relating to your participation in the Learning Tools. We keep this personally-identifiable information on our servers for a period of 3 years. After this period is over, the data will be backed up to tape backup media and stored offline. 

All credit card payments are timely processed using third-party gateways. Once the credit/debit card information is processed, the transaction is deleted from our electronic database and is kept only with the credit/debit card processor, not on our servers. 

Marketplace Simulations does not knowingly collect personally-identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. 

### 2\. Anonymous collection of information

Our web server collects and stores the following general information about you: the originating name of the domain from which you access the Internet; the date and time you access our service; the pages you visit; the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to us; the name and version of the web browser software you are using. This information is collected automatically. It is used to help us improve our Sites by tabulating the number of visitors to our Sites in terms of new users, origin of referrers, popularity of pages, amount of use, and types of errors, in addition to making the Sites more useful to you. 

### 3\. Use of cookies

We use “cookies,” which are small files stored on your computer's hard drive that are used to store and track personal information. Many browsers can notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the option to accept it or not. By not accepting cookies, you may not be permitted to access certain information and some Site pages may not display properly. 

### 4\. Using Information About You

When you provide your contact information to us, or request information about our products, we will enter your contact information in our database of inquiries. We use this information to: 

  * process sales and support requests;
  * create instructor and learner accounts;
  * send newsletters;
  * send game management related notifications; and
  * process payments to Marketplace Simulations.

Marketplace Simulations acknowledges that EU and Swiss individuals protected by the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks have the right to access or limit the use or disclosure of the personal information that we maintain about them. An EU individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data, should direct their query to support@marketplace-simulation.com. If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe. 

If you are located in European Union (“EU”), the European Economic Area (“EEA”), or Switzerland, we share this information with our applicable EU, EEA, and Swiss distributor(s) to contact you with news and special offers to follow up on your request. You may always unsubscribe to these news or offers by removing your personally identifiable information using the method below or by clicking the “unsubscribe” link in any email. 

Employees of Marketplace Simulations who have access to any of your personal information in connection with the Marketplace Simulations are not permitted to use this information for any other purpose than to carry out services on behalf of Marketplace Simulations. We share information about your participation in the Learning Tools with your game instructor (professor) and/or other applicable faculty of your educational institution. We share your name with other users to help those users identify the proper game and team to join. 

We gather additional information for remarketing or similar audiences on the Sites. This allows us to advertise to people who previously visited the Sites. We engage third-party vendors, such as Google, to provide remarketing services on our behalf. 

We will not seek to gather additional information from third parties or enhance or merge personally-identifiable information with data obtained from third parties. We will not give or sell your personally-identifiable information to any outside organization. 

We will provide information to regulatory authorities and law enforcement officials when permitted or required by applicable law, or when we otherwise believe in good faith that the law requires it. If necessary, we will access or disclose your information in order to protect or defend the legal rights or property of Marketplace Simulations and its affiliated companies or their employees and agents, to protect the safety and security of users, and to protect against fraud. 

We also may be required to disclose an individual’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 

We may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of our assets in connection with a merger, reorganization or sale of assets, or in the event of bankruptcy. In such an event, personal information may be one of the assets transferred. 

We may transfer your personal information for the purposes described in our Privacy Policy to a third party acting as a data controller or as an agent. If we disclose personal information to a third party acting as a data controller or as an agent, we will comply with and protect the information as provided in the Accountability for Onward Transfer Principle and our agreement(s) with you. 

When EU and Swiss data subjects’ personal information received under the Privacy Shield is subsequently transferred to a third party acting as an agent and if the agent processes such personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, we may be liable with respect to the onward transfer of such information, unless we prove that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. 

### 5\. Security of information

Marketplace Simulations seeks to keep your information protected. We have gone to great lengths to protect the data residing on our web servers, including firewalling our servers and encrypting all data transfers. However, no transmission can be totally secure; therefore, we cannot guarantee 100% security of your data. 

### 6\. Third Party Websites

This Privacy Policy is applicable only to the Sites and does not apply to any third party websites or to other companies or persons. The Sites may contain links to, and media and other content from, other sites. In addition, such third-party media and content may also contain external links. Marketplace Simulations cannot and does not guarantee the privacy policies and practices of any third party. Marketplace Simulations does not control, operate, or endorse any information, products, or services of any third-party websites that may be reached through links from the Site. The use of any personal information provided by you to such a third party will be governed by that party's privacy policy. You should review the privacy policy at each linked website to determine how that website treats your personal information. 

Marketplace Simulations will require its agents to safeguard personal information consistent with this Privacy Policy by contract obligating the agent to provide at least the same level of protection as is required by the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Principles. 

In connection with our remarketing activities, third-party websites, such as Google, Bing, etc. show our advertisements on websites across the Internet. These third-party websites use cookies or similar tracking technologies to serve advertisements based on your interests and your past visits to the Sites. We do not control third parties' collection or use of your information to serve interest-based advertising. However, these third parties may provide you with ways to choose not to have your information collected or used in this way. You can opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting Google's Ads Settings (located at http://www.google.com/settings/ads). You can opt out of receiving targeted advertisements from members of the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI") on the NAI's website (located at http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). 

### 7\. Visiting our Site from outside the United States

If you are visiting this Site from outside the United States, please be aware that your information will be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our central database is operated. By using our services, you understand and consent to your information being transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Privacy Policy.

### 8\. Privacy Shield

Marketplace Simulations complies with the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks, as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information (“Personal Information”) from member countries of the EU, the EEA, and Switzerland. Marketplace Simulations has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the policies in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/. To view our Privacy Shield certification, please visit www.privacyshield.gov/list. 

Marketplace Simulations’ participation in the Privacy Shield applies to personal data received from the EU, the EEA, and/or Switzerland. Marketplace Simulations will comply with the Privacy Shield Principles in respect of such personal data. Some types of Personal Information may be subject to additional privacy-related requirements and policies, which are consistent with the Privacy Shield Principles, including, but not limited to, specific contractual obligations, additional applicable laws and professional standards, Marketplace Simulations’ internal policies, and this Privacy Policy. 

In implementing the Privacy Shield Principles, Marketplace Simulations has agreed to subject its compliance to the full breadth of regulatory enforcement of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) or any other statutory body empowered to enforce compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles. 

Marketplace Simulations remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if third party agents that it engages to process personal data on its behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles, unless Marketplace Simulations proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. 

If you have any questions or complaints about our compliance with the Privacy Shield, please contact us using the contact information provided below. 

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Marketplace Simulations commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. EU or Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Marketplace Simulations using the contact information provided below. 

Marketplace Simulations has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus to service complaints involving EU or Swiss individuals. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers for more information and to file a complaint. 

Under certain limited circumstances, if all other remedies have been exhausted to no avail, EU individuals may invoke binding Privacy Shield arbitration as a last resort. Please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction for information on when you may invoke binding arbitration. To initiate binding arbitration, you must give notification of this decision to Marketplace Simulations using the contact information provided below. 

General information about the Privacy Shield and the Privacy Shield Principles, as well as information about binding Privacy Shield arbitration, can be found at www.privacyshield.gov. 

### 9\. Your California Rights

If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your personally identifiable by Marketplace Simulations to a third party for the third party's direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us using the contact information provided below. 

### 10\. Amendment

This Privacy Policy may be amended consistent with the requirements of the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks. When we update this Privacy Policy, we will also revise the "Last Updated" date at the top of this document. 

### 11\. Contacting us regarding your personally-identifiable information

To request that your information be deleted or corrected, send a letter to:  
Marketplace Simulations  
Attn: Technical Support  
520 W Summit Hill Rd, Suite 701  
Knoxville, TN 37902  
USA  
Email Address: support@marketplace-simulation.com  
Telephone number: +1 (865) 522 1946  
We will then use reasonable efforts to remove your personal information from our files and/or database. You may also contact us through any of the above methods to request information about the knowledge we have about you in our database. 

Last updated 07/02/2018
